A Guide to the Tavenner Genealogical Collection 1918-1986
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Tavenner Genealogical Collection ca. 1918-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11151
This collection contains approximately 665 items within 6 Hollinger boxes, totaling 2.5 linear feet.
This collection consists of the genealogical research of Charles Blair Tavenner (d. 1980) of Alexandria, Virginia, ca. 1918-1986, ca. 665 items (6 Hollinger boxes, 2.5 linear feet), chiefly pertaining to residents of Loudoun County, Virginia.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were bequeathed to the University of Virginia Library on November 17, 1994, by Phronie A. Tavenner of Alexandria, Virginia.
Biographical/Historical Information
Charles B. Tavenner of Alexendria, Virginia, died in 1980.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the genealogical research of Charles Blair Tavenner (d. 1980) of Alexandria, Virginia, ca. 1918-1986, ca. 665 items (6 Hollinger boxes, 2.5 linear feet), chiefly pertaining to residents of Loudoun County, Virginia. The collection includes 21 bound notebooks, fourteen of which list alphabetically all known white adults who lived in Loudoun County prior to 1900 (the volume for "T" residents consists of copies only placed in a folder); one containing research on the Northern Neck Land Patents for what became Loudoun County; two with research concerning land patents for Loudoun County, arranged alphabetically; alphabetical lists of the Heads of Families in Loudoun County in 1810 and of wills, 1757-1890; one with Loudoun County Estate Names; one with indexes of names appearing on the Yardley Taylor Map and in V.V. Purcell's Account Book (1842-1847); and a final volume of miscellaneous notes concerning Loudoun County.
The Tavenner papers also contain miscellaneous notes; modern hand-drawn plats of properties in Loudoun County, Virginia, arranged alphabetically by the name of the owner; two typed documents entitled "Inscriptions Old Ebenezer Cemetery Bloomfield" and "Inscriptions Old Bethesda Methodist Cemetery; copies of land patents from the Virginia State Library concerning the Fairfax Grants; and notes concerning deeds, land patents, and order books pertaining to Loudoun County, as well as miscellaneous notes about Loudoun County history. Also present are notes concerning deeds in Prince William County and Fairfax County, Virginia, for areas that later became Loudoun County. There is also a small amount of correspondence pertaining to the Tavenner Project concerning Phronie A. Tavenner's efforts to have her husband's genealogical work published by the Loudoun County Historical Society after his death.
Contents List
- Bound Volumes
  - Research re: white residents of Loudoun County, Virginia, "A" - "R" (12 volumes) ca. 1930-1980 (Box 1)
  - Research re: white residents of Loudoun County, Virginia, "S" - "Z" (2 volumes) ca. 1930 - 1980 (Box 2)
  - Research re: Northern Neck Land Patents for what became Loudoun County, Virginia (Fairfax Grants) ca. 1930 - 1980 (Box 2)
  - Research re: Land Patents for Loudoun County, Virginia, "A-M" ca. 1930 - 1980 (Box 2)
  - Research re: Land Patents for Loudoun County, Virginia, "N-Z," & including Fairfax & Prince William County ca. 1930 - 1980 (Box 2)
  - Alphabetical List of Heads of Families in Loudoun County, Virginia, 1810 & Alphabetical List of Wills, 1757-1890 ca. 1930 - 1980 (Box 2)
  - Research re Loudoun County, Virginia, Estate Names ca. 1930 - 1980 (Box 2)
  - Indexes of Names Appearing on the Yardley Taylor Map of Loudoun County & Names in V.V. Purcell's Account Book (1842-1847) ca. 1930 - 1980 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Notes re: Loudoun County, Virginia ca. 1930 - 1980 (Box 2)
- Foldered Items
  - Research re: white Residents of Loudoun County, Virginia, Volume "T" (Copy) ca. 1930 - 1980 (Box 2)
  - "Inscriptions Old Betheseda Methodist Cemetery" by Inez Harrison Beavers 1957 (Box 2)
  - "Inscriptions Old Ebenezer Cemetery - Bloomfield" compiled by Welby Sowers and Mary Alice Wertz, with index, 17 pages n.d. (Box 2)
  - Land Patents (Copies from the Virginia State Library) Fairfax Grants (6 folders) ca. 1973 (Box 3)
  - Newsclippings and Printed Material re Loudoun County, Virginia 1918 - 1976 (Box 4)
  - Notes re: Loudoun County, Virginia Deeds, 827 pages (5 folders) n.d. (Box 4)
  - Notes re: Loudoun County, Virginia Land Patents n.d. (Box 4)
  - Notes re: Loudoun County, Virginia - Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1940 - 1953, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Notes re: Loudoun County, Virginia - Order Books, 1757-1776 n.d. (Box 5)
  - Notes re: Prince William County, Virginia Deeds, 1732-1742 and Fairfax County, Virginia Deeds, 1742-1757 n.d. (Box 5)
  - Plats of Properties in Loudoun County, Virginia (Modern Hand-drawn) - Miscellaneous and Adams-Clarke (2 folders) n.d. (Box 5)
  - Plats of Properties in Loudoun County, Virginia (Modern Hand-drawn) Cocke-Yeardley (6 folders) n.d. (Box 6)
  - Tavenner Project Correspondence 1980 - 1986 (Box 6)